TIMOTHY E. ILOBA

Certified Full Stack Web Developer

ilobatimothy@gmail.com https://sney.netlify.app +234(0) 818 5375 580

ABOUT ME

Young, dedicated and proficient full stack developer with 4+ years experience in Full stack web Development. Knowledgeable with ability to create, great problem solving skills and deep understanding of the software development process. Capable of working with a variety of technologies, software solutions and database management.

WORK EXPERIENCES

1. Full Stack Developer (Remote)

Rooah LLC Dover, Delaware (USA). October 2021 - Date

Key Responsibilities/Achievements

- Wrote/Modified new modules for required projects utilizing PHP Laravel and JavaScript
- Responded to user feedback and reviews to help implement updates and fix bugs
- Maintained, updated and improved on platform projects.
- Monitored critical systems daily and responded quickly to any security breaches or usability concerns.
- Maintained website infrastructure on the AWS platform.
- Translated Interface design to pixel perfect mobile responsive web pages

.

2. Full Stack Developer (Remote)

Trenova Consulting, Lagos Nigeria. January 2021 - October 2021

Key Responsibilities/Achievements

- Worked in a team and developed a School E-reading Platform for Kids using PHP (Wordpress).
- Maximized applications' efficiency, data quality, scope, operability, and flexibility.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades

3. Full Stack Developer

Bellonix Integrated Technologies, Kaduna. December 2019-December 2020

Key Responsibilities/Achievements

- Developed a school E-report and management information system using PHP (Laravel).
- Maximized applications' efficiency, data quality, scope, operability, and flexibility.
- Managed, optimized, and updated PHP (Mysql) databases as necessary.
- Developed app integration with REST / SOAP and other APIs for Google Maps, social media logins, payment processors, and other services.

4. Frontend Developer

August 2019 - December 2019 IT Central, Kaduna, Nigeria.

Key Responsibilities/Achievements

- Designed school result templates for School portal kits using Html and CSS.
- Worked with Vue on a Content management system (CMS) Project.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.
- Built the user interfaces (UI) for some web projects.

EDUCATION

Diploma in Software Development

Toxaswift Schools, Kaduna Nigeria.

Graduation: 2018

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, MVC Architecture, Website design and Development, Wordpress web development, Graphics design, Relational Database

Design & SQL, Data Engineering, Advanced Software Programming.

KEY SKILLS

- Problem Solving Skills
- Understanding of Data Structures and Algorithms
- Code refactoring and ability to write clean code
- Knowledge of Solid Principles
- Understanding of DevOps
- Code Testing
- Ability to learn fast
- Graphics design Skills (Corel draw & Photoshop)

KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED

- PHP (Laravel)
- Html, CSS, Sass & JavaScript (Vue JS)
- Bootstrap & Tailwind CSS
- Wordpress
- SQL Databases (Mysql)
- Git and Github

CERTIFICATIONS

- Full-Stack Web Development Certificate
- Graphics design Certificate

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

English Language